A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - S-T, 2.8
    - Stark, Sheldon, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9748)
      Interview. Stark was a classmate of Nelson Rockefeller at the Lincoln School in Manhattan and Dartmouth College.
    - Stassen, Harold, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9749)
      Interview. As delegate at the conference that established the United Nations in 1945, Stassen was one of eight Americans who signed the UN Charter. (Nelson Rockefeller attended as well). Stassen then served in the adminstration of President Dwight D. Eisenhower for 5 years and unsuccessfully sought the Republican nomination for President 9 times between 1948 and 1988.
    - Steingut, Stanley, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9750)
      Interview. Steingut was a Democratic member of the New York state Assembly who served as Speaker of the Assembly in the 1970s. Previously, he was Brooklyn Democratic party chair.
    - Stephenson, Sir William, 1982 September 27; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9751)
      Interview. Stephenson was British Prime Minister William Churchill's secret intelligence ambassdor to President Franklin D. Roosevelt. At the direction of Churchill, Stephenson established and ran the British Security Coordination, which was a covert organization operated out of Rockefeller Center with a purpose of investigating enemy activities, preventing sabotage against British interests in the Americas, and mobilizing pro-British opinion in the Americas. Stephenson supplied Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs Nelson Rockefeller with information on Nazi commercial activities in Latin America.
    - Stewart, Dick, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9752)
      Interview. From 1963-1967, Stewart was assistant, then first assistant counsel to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, and then became New York State Insurance Commissioner, 1967-1970.
    - Stone, Robert - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9753)
      Interview. Stone served as Executive Deputy Secretary of State and then Deputy Commissioner of General Services under Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Stone interview ends at 86 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Mike Scelsi until end. Scelsi was executive director of the New York State Republican Committee, 1959-1965. Then after serving as Appointments Officer for two years, Governor Nelson Rockefeller appointed Scelsi to the New York State Civil Service Commission.
    - Stone, Robert - Part 2, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9754)
      Interview. Stone served as Executive Deputy Secretary of State and then Deputy Commissioner of General Services under Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Stone interview ends at 40 minutes, 23 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Abby O'Neill until end. O'Neill was Nelson Rockefeller's niece.
    - Storrow, Linda Jamieson, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9755)
      Interview. Storrow worked in Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; spouse of Public Relations Director (Frank Jamieson) for Nelson Rockefeller's first campaign for the U.S. presidency in 1960. After Mr. Jameison died of cancer in 1960, Governor Rockefeller appointed Storrow the state's official greeter of foreign dignitaries to the city of New York.
    - Sutton, Percy, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9756)
      Interview. Sutton was a Democratic New York State Assemblyman, 1965-1966, and Manhattan borough president, 1966-1977.
    - Taylor, Arthur, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9757)
      Interview. The former president of Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS), Taylor co-founded the Sarabam Corporation with Nelson Rockefeller in the late 1970s. Taylor interview ends at 32 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Joseph Crangle until end. Crangle was New York State Democratic chair.
    - Teller, Edward - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9758A)
      Interview. Teller was a member of the Manhattan Project during World War II and a panelist on the International Security Objectives and Strategy subpanel of Nelson Rockefeller's Special Studies project in the late 1950s, funded by the Rockefeller Brother's Fund.
    - Teller, Edward - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 9 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9758B)
    - Terry, Jack, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9759)
      Interview. Terry was Assistant Secretary to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller from 1959 to 1961. He later served as a Republican in the New York State Assembly and then one term in the U.S. House of Representatives.
    - Thaler, Manley, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9760)
      Interview. Thaler was Republican Party chair of Tompkins County (NY).
    - Thorne, Craig, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9761)
      Interview. Thorne was a campaign aide and advance man for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Tofany, Vincent, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9762)
      Interview. Tofany was Republican Party chairman of Monroe County during the 1966 New York gubernatorial election.
    - Troy, Matthew, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9763)
      Interview. Troy was a Democratic New York City councilman from Queens, 1964-1977, and the leader of the Queens Democratic Party, 1971-1974.
    - Trubin, John - Interview 1, 1982; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9764A)
      Interview. Trubin was campaign aide for Governor Nelson Rockefeller who was responsible for negotiating the terms for televised debates.
    - Trubin, John - Interview 2, 1982 April 15; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9764B)
      Interview. Trubin was a campaign aide for Governor Nelson Rockefeller who was responsible for negotiating the terms for televised debates.
  - U-Z, 2.9
    - Underhill, Jacob, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9765)
      Interview. Underhill was a national affairs writer for Newsweek and then an assistant press secretary for Governor Nelson Rockefeller during the 1964 and 1968 presidential campaigns and the 1966 New York gubernatorial campaign.
    - Unidentified, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9766)
      Interview. Tape contains two interviews with unidentified individuals from Batterymarch Financial Management regarding investing and trading. The first interview ends at 40 minutes, 10 seconds.
    - Unidentified, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9767)
      Interview. Tape contains two interivews with unidentified individuals from General Motors. First interivew ends at 11 minutes, 30 seconds.
    - Urstadt, Charles, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9768)
      Interview. Urstadt was deputy commissioner of the division of housing and community renewal, 1967-1969, and then commissioner, 1969-1973. He also helped found the Urban Development Corporation and was chairman of the Battery Park City Authority, 1968-1979.
    - Van Dyk, Ted, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9770)
      Interview. Van Dyk was a senior aide to Vice President Hubert Humphrey and an author. Van Dyk interview ends at 27 minutes, 39 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Gwirtzman until end. Gwirtzman was an advisor and speech writer for John, Robert, and Edward Kennedy.
    - Van Lare, Barry, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9774)
      Interview. Van Lare was a consultant to states on welfare and related human services programs. He served as executive deputy commissioner and then acting commissioner of the New York Sate Department of Social Services.
    - Van Ness, Edward, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9771)
      Interview. Van Ness worked on various health and human services issues in the Program Office and the New York State Health Department, including drug addiction, Medicaid, and Governor Nelson Rockefeller's push for universal health insurance.
    - Vanden Heuvel, William, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9772)
      Interview. Vanden Heuvel was special counsel to Governor Averell Harriman in 1958. In 1960, he ran for Congress as a Democrat against Republican incumbent John Lindsay in New York City's 17th Congressional District and lost. In the 1970s, vanden Heuvel served as chairman of the New York City Board of Corrections and, in 1973, challenged but lost to incumbent Frank Hogan in the Democratic Primary for Manhattan District Attorney.
    - Vandervoort, Jack, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9773)
      Interview. Vandervoort was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Vandervoort interview ends at 153 minutes, 50 seconds. Tape then contains phone call with Reich and a woman at the Lyndon Baines Johnson Library until 160 minutes, 3 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Harry Albright until end. Albright was an aide to Nelson Rockefeller, 1967-1975. During Rockefeller's governorship, Albright held various positions, including deputy secretary, executive secretary, and appointments officer. He was also state banking superintendent, 1972-1974. He then served has Rockefeller's special counsel when Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - von Hirsch, Andrew, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9578)
      Interview. Von Hirsch was an aide to Senator Charles Goodell, a Republican from New York who was appointed by Governor Nelson Rockefeller to fill the Senate seat following the assassination of Senator Robert F. Kennedy. Von Hirsch interview ends at 84 minutes, 30 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Sam Gould until 93 minutes, 21 seconds. Gould was chancellor of the State University of New York. Tape then contains partial interview with von Hirsch until 130 minutes, 25 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Hayward Plumadore until end. Plumadore was Franklin County Republican chairman.
    - Wagner, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9775)
      Interview. Wagner (a Democrat) was mayor of New York from 1954 to 1965. Wagner interview ends at 68 minutes, 16 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudley until end. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany.
    - Walker, Wyatt Tee, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9776)
      Interview. Walker was pastor of the Canaan Baptist Church in Harlem, 1967-2004. In the early 1970s, he was an urban affairs specialist for Governor Nelson Rockefeller. In 1971, he was one of the negotiators who met with leaders of the Attica prison uprising. Before coming to New York, Walker was one of the founders of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC). In 1960, he became the executive director of SCLC and Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.'s chief of staff.
    - Wallis, Jim, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9777)
      Interview. Wallis was Nelson Rockefeller's nephew. Wallis interview ends at 128 minutes, 42 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Louis Levine until 134 minutes, 34 seconds. Levine was New York State Industrial Commissioner, 1966-1976. Tape then contains partial interview with Ogden Reid until 143 minutes, 43 seconds. Reid was appointed to the New York State Commission on Discrimination in 1961 by Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Reid also served six terms in the United States House of Representatives, 1963-1975. He switched from Republican to Democrat in 1972. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudely until end. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany.
    - Wallison, Peter, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9778)
      Interview. Wallison was special assistant to Nelson Rockefeller, 1971-1976, and counsel to Vice President Rockefeller, 1972-1976.
    - Walsh, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9779)
      Interview. Walsh worked as an assistant attorney general prior to Nelson Rockefeller's tenure and then served in Governor Rockefeller's administrations in as an assistant appointments officer and advance man.
    - Warburg, Edward, 1982 March 30; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9780)
      Interview. Warburg was a philanthropist and friend of Nelson Rockefeller. He served on the board of trustees at the Museum of Modern Art, 1932-1958, and was a trustee and organizer of MoMA's film library. He was also vice director for public affairs of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1971-1974. In addition, Warburg was a co-founder of the American Ballet and the School of American Ballet.
    - Watts, Bill, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9781)
      Interview. Watts was director of the Office for Urban Innovationunder for Governor Nelson Rockefeller in the late 1960s. Watts then was staff secretary of Presdient Richard Nixon's National Security Council for 18 months before resigning to protest planned military operations in Cambodia.
    - Weaver, Sylvester (Pat), circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9782)
      Interview. Weaver was a Dartmouth classmate of and later a campaign advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. He was a pioneer in U.S. television broadcasting, serving as the president of the National Broadcasting Company (NBC) in the 1950s.
    - Weaver, Warren, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9783)
      Interview. Weaver was a reporter in the Washington Bureau of the New York Times who covered Nelson Rockefeller for many years as Governor of New York and presidential candidate.
    - Webb, Charles, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9784)
      Interview. Webb was counsel to New York State Assemblyman Perry Duryea and worked on the reapportionment of legislature districts.
    - Weinstein, Moses, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9785)
      Interview. Weinstein was a Democratic member of the New York State Assembly in the 1960s and majority leader and from 1965 to 1968. In 1969, he was elected to the New York State Supreme Court.
    - Wharton, Clifton, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9786)
      Interview. Wharton worked for the American International Association for Economic and Social Development, 1948-1953. He served as associate, then as director of operations for the American Development Council, 1958-1964. He was a member of the Rockefeller presidential mission to Latin America in 1969. In October 1969, Wharton was elected president of Michigan State University, thereby becoming the first African-American president of a major United States university. In 1978, he became chancellor of the State University of New York system. In 1982, Wharton was named chairman of the Rockefeller Foundation.
    - White, F. Clifton - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9787A)
      Interview. White was a political consultant and campaign manager for Republican Party and New York Conservative Party candidates. He was also a leader of the Draft Goldwater Committee, 1961-1964.
    - White, F. Clifton - Part 2, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9787B)
    - Whiteman, Michael, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9788)
      Interview. Whiteman worked on Governor Nelson Rockfeller's staff in various capacities from 1963 to 1973, including as confidential law assistant and his fourth Counsel to the Governor. He was then Counsel to Governor Malcolm Wilson.
    - Whitney, Marylou, 1982 September 17; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9790)
    - Widmayer, Charles, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9791)
      Interview. Widmayer was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Wiebe, Richard, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9792)
      Interview. Wiebe served under Nelson Rockefeller in the New York State Program Office on the program that led to the Pure Waters Act; also on the Adirondacks Park Commission. Wiebe interview ends at 155 minutes, 15 seconds. Tape then contains partial interivew with Joan Braden until end. Braden was a friend of Nelson Rockefeller and a Rockefeller family aide.
    - Wiggin, J. Walker, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9793)
      Interview. Wiggin was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Williams, Nadia, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9794)
      Interview. Williams was on Nelson Rockefeller's staff at the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) and the U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW).
    - Wilson, Lois, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9795)
      Interview. Wilson was a deputy secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefelelr and then special assistant for education to Governors Rockefeller and Hugh Carey. Wilson interview ends at 45 minutes, 16 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Roswell Perkins until end. Perkins was assistant secretary at the Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1953-1956, and counsel to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1958-1959.
    - Wilson, Malcom - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9796)
      Interview. Wilson was Lieutenant Governor of New York during all four of Nelson Rockefeller's terms as Governor, 1959 to 1973. When Rockefeller resigned in 1973, Wilson succeeded him into office. He lost election to the office in 1974. He had started in public service in the New York State Assembly from 1939 to 1958.
    - Wilson, Malcolm - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9797)
      Wilson interiview ends at 67 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with John Lockwood until 93 minutes, 33 seconds. Lockwood was chief legal adviser to the Rockefeller family and chair of the New York Public Library. Tape then continues with Wilson interview until end.
    - Wodell, Margaret, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9798)
      Interview. Wodell was a friend of Nelson Rockefeller's family in Seal Harbor, Maine. Wodell interview ends at 23 minutes, 25 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with William Sharkey. Sharkey was chief of revenue estimating for the New York State Department of Taxation and Finance prior to Nelson Rockefeller's administration. He then served in Governor Rockefeller's office starting in 1959, where he focused on tax and budgeting projects.
    - Wolfgang, Jerry, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9799)
      Interview. Wolfgang was an advance man for Nelson Rockefeller's gubernatorial campaigns as well as for Governor Rockefeller's 1969 fact-finding mission to Argentina that looked into the embattled military government of Juan Carlos Ongania.
    - Zimmerman, Donald, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9800)
      Interview. Zimmmerman was a lawyer in the Appellate Division of the New York State Supreme Court, eventually rising to chief law assistant. He was then a New York State Supreme Court Justice in the Bronx and counsel to the New York State Republican Senate majority leadership. Zimmerman also served as counsel to the Joint Legislative Committee on Reapportionment and worked on the Waterfront Commmission.